<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iTunes | Arsham Skrenes]]></title>
  <link href="http://arsham.skrenes.com/blog/categories/itunes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://arsham.skrenes.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-15T13:37:10-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://arsham.skrenes.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Arsham Skrenes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iTunes, Media Keys, and IntelliType]]></title>
    <link href="http://arsham.skrenes.com/blog/2011/10/22/mediakeys/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-22T13:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://arsham.skrenes.com/blog/2011/10/22/mediakeys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve never been too impressed with iTunes since it was made. I was always a Winamp user myself. It&rsquo;s quite disappointing that features such as popup jump lists, accessible from anywhere, are still not in iTunes over a decade later. Sadly, iTunes hasn&rsquo;t changed all that much over the years. One of things they seem to have always had a trouble with is media keys (play/next-track/prev-track) on keyboards. It seemed that iTunes 9+ fixed the issues but iTunes 10.5 seems to have broken it again with people using Microsoft&rsquo;s IntelliType (version 8.2 at the time of writing this). <strong>Although the media keys still work when iTunes 10.5 is the active window, it does not work when iTunes is not the active window.</strong></p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>All this program does is fire the standard hardware scan code for the respective argument. The benefit of this is it not only works with iTunes 10.5, <strong>it works with any application</strong>. You can even create a desktop shortcut and make your own special key sequence to invoke say <strong>mediakeys.exe play</strong> which would toggle play/pause in any media application or <strong>mediakeys.exe next</strong> on a keyboard that doesn&rsquo;t have a &ldquo;next-track&rdquo; button. This utility should work with any kind of keyboard and doesn&rsquo;t require IntelliType.</p>

<p>If you have a Microsoft keyboard with IntelliType, like I do (Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000), then these screen shots show you how you can configure it:</p>

<p><img class="borderless" src="/blog/images/MediaKeys1.png" width="390">
<img class="borderless" src="/blog/images/MediaKeys2.png" width="390">
<img class="borderless" src="/blog/images/MediaKeys3.png" width="390">
<img class="borderless" src="/blog/images/MediaKeys4.png" width="390"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
